ANDREY GOLUBENKO

golubenko98@gmail.com \leftrightarrow linkedin.com/in/aagolubenko/

OBJECTIVE

Currently I have 2.5 years of experience with iOS apps of different scale that enables me to design adjustable architecture for particular projects. Also I have a basic expertise of backend development (Docker, Flask, SQL) that helps me to perceive the development process generally.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics and Computer Engineering, Higher School of Economics

On academic leave

TOOLS AND LANGUAGES

Swift, Objective-C, Python 3,

UIKit, SwiftUI, Combine, Core Data, Swift Package Manager,

Firebase, MessageKit, Backend-driven UI, UDF, Storyboard, SnapKit, Proxyman, Charles

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer May 2022 - Current

Adamant Blockchain Messenger

- Improved stability and security of messenger by implementing nodes health check
- Found and fixed possibility of MITM attack
- Adopted messenger for using on MacOS
- Fixed working of push notifications and chat UI
- Introduced scrum methodology to our team
- Moved project to Combine and SwiftUI

iOS Developer

February 2021 - April 2022

Yandex main app

- Implemented video section in this app
- Added possibility to add different images for each theme in Yandex backend-driven UI framework (DivKit)
- Implemented a unified navigation design for the entire super app
- Added swiping instruments to Yandex backend-driven UI framework
- Introduced various types of cards and popups into the main feed

iOS Developer + backend developer

March 2021 - January 2021

Cloud 53 lounge bar

- Implemented 2 versions of application
- Added progressive loyalty system with ability of scanning customer's QR codes
- Introduced parking booking system
- Added administrator panel via Telegram bot
- Implemented fully backend-driven content layout
- Authorization via Apple ID and phone number